

SUMMARY

I'm creative and an organized and efficient problem solver with a proven track record of solving strategic and tactical challenges at small, large, and mid-size companies. I excel in sales, account management, data analysis, B2B marketing and business strategy, but I have a unique skill set. I've worked closely with product teams and recently completed a programming bootcamp. I'm able to manage projects, conduct user research, design products, and build web applications. Above all, I'm a hustler. I work hard and am someone you want in your corner.

SOFT SKILLS

LEADERSHIP

LISTENING

PROBLEM SOLVING

COMMUNICATION

HARD SKILLS

PROJECT
MANAGEMENT

RESEARCH

DESIGN

DEVELOPMENT

SALES ENABLEMENT

DATA ANALYTICS

TOOLS & LANGUAGES

SKETCH

ADOBE SUITE

RUBY ON RAILS

JAVASCRIPT

HTML & CSS

SQL

THOMAS PATTON

PRODUCT MARKETING MANAGER

408.355.4309 | 207 W 10th Street, New York City, NY, 10014 | tom.patton22@gmail.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

HotelTonight | Regional Manager | September 2017- August 2018

- Sized MidWest market opportunity, hired and managed four-person team, and drove regional revenue growth to the top 25% in the company.
- Managed quarterly, bottom-up forecast for regional revenue, take rate, and conversion targets.
 96% forecast accuracy.
- Developed sales and feature up-selling strategy/sub KPIs to topline targets—region was top
 10% for feature adoption growth YoY and sales-per-head.
- Researched, built, user tested, and scaled "behind the curtain" partner competition tool that
 increased revenue for 300+ partners by 20% above the mean: prototyped product integration
 that won internal Data & Strategy Hackathon and was added to the product roadmap.

HotelTonight | Account & Business Development Manager | 2015-2017

- Top performance in achieving business results, team collaboration, and partner engagement led
 to rapid promotion into increasingly important markets: Los Angeles (Top 2), San Diego (Top 5)
 and Palm Springs (Top 10), New Orleans (Top 20).
- Collaborated with marketing, data, and product teams, to gather user feedback, produce product one-pagers, and sell features for 10+ product launches.
- In tandem with CTO, CFO, and Director of Data & Strategy, led focus group to analyze, A/B test, and optimize conversion for hotel listing algorithm.
- Researched, prototyped, developed, tested, and revised automated hotel productivity reporting
 and inventory tracking spreadsheets which led to a 10% increase in partner production. Tools
 productized in Tableau and scaled to the 100+ person supply team.

Google I Social Media Specialist I 2014-2015

- Gathered product feedback and addressed concerns for Google Glass users on social platforms with a combined 1M followers.
- Designed video and graphic content for 50+ social media interactions.

Cisco | Education Marketing Intern | Summer, 2012 & Summer, 2011

- Led four-member intern team which produced and presented product marketing strategy
 (competitive analysis, feature recommendations, target markets, and go-to-market plan) to ten
 Cisco executives.
- Analyzed education survey containing 2000+ data points of educator thoughts and pain-points.
 Created 15 page white paper mapping customer pain points to Cisco technologies and success stories.

EDUCATION

Le Wagon Full-Stack Development Bootcamp | August 2018 - September 2018

- Two month product bootcamp that focused on web development (Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Javascript, HTML & CSS, and SQL), product design, and product management.
- Developed two fully functional web app MVPs from product definition (user stories, customer
 journey, prototyping, user-testing, and product backlog) to production, and deployment.

University of Oregon | 2010 - 2014

Major in International Studies with a focus in International Business. Minor in Business, Marketing

La Sorbonne I 2013 - 2013

• Intensive French Language and Culture

SOCIAL